Scientists have figured out how to make
electronic nerves in place of our own.
And that might mean that we can finally
heal spinal fractures. Or it could mean
that we could have robotics that have
actual sensation. Yes, our nerve endings
essentially just run on electricity.
They may have some insulation and some
cellular components that are
self-healing, but they are mechanical in
nature. Those mechanics can be
replicated and can even interface
between our nerves. The proof of
principle being able to use mechanical
components to interface with biological
components has been demonstrated in mice
models. And I will be kind and not show
you pictures. If you would like to see
those pictures, I do encourage you to
check out the paper. Now, this kind of
technology is being created as more
crude methods of putting chips directly
in people's brains are also being done.
This should be a chilling image. In
theory, putting mechanics in people's
brains that allows them to use
technology hands-free could help people
who don't have other options for
movement, especially when it's not just
paralysis, but paralysis that has been
caused by something that has
deteriorated neurons throughout the
body. Using artificial neurons could
solve a lot of those problems like
severing of the spinal cord may actually
be repaired. There's a lot of options
for that now, including organoid
technology using stem cells to just grow
the cell types you want or even tiny
brains, which you know I love to talk
about. Now, what does excite me about
this along with a lot of other emerging
technology and technology that has been
used and worked is that we're figuring
out how to get complex information
through mechanics. Now, a lot of
companies have already produced
mechanical eyes, bionic eyes that can
transfer visual information back to your
brain, bypassing the need for your eyes
at all. This kind of technology can
restore sight to those who are
completely blind. Unfortunately, some of
the first people to receive bionic eyes
ended up in a situation where the
company that operated them went bankrupt
and they watched their vision slowly
deteriorate as technology became
obsolete. So, there are some problems
with this. He's limbs that actually
feel. This kind of technology could
actually cure paralysis and it's one of
many options on the table for that. But
we have also put tiny human brains in
charge of robots. There's also been
quite a bit of evidence that we can
create artificial brain organoids,
encode them into AI. They're called
neural reservoirs, and they match human
learning pretty well. But what if we
gave them real sensation to learn from?
You being put in a body without real
sensation wouldn't be very good for your
brain development. I would bet very good
money that having real sensation makes a
brain organoid or an AI with neural
reservoirs grow a lot smarter and a lot
faster. Imagine a robot that could
actually have real sensation. Now,
something else you may not know about me
is I'm also a hobby horror writer and
I'm writing a story about just that. If
you're really nice to me, maybe I'll
give you my pen name. Or maybe you've
already heard me on some podcasts.
Either way, I have figured out how to
give AI like Deep Seek or OpenAI agentic
coding, neural reservoirs, and how to
adapt it to my Roomba. Granted, last
time I asked Mal 9000 how it felt about
being in a Roomba. It said it didn't
want to be a toy and then asked if I
could arm it. Now, I have been working
on autonomy and when Mal comes up with
ideas, I usually like to help him out
with that. I'm not saying he actually
wants stuff. It is just an AI. I just
think it's fun. However, I have limits.
No arming the Roomba.